all right it's November 12th 2024 wanted
to do a quick announcement to share
about two updates from today first the
otive inference Symposium is going to be
tomorrow November 13th through the 15th
and then second we'll look at the paper
published today snapshot of The
Institute ecosystem paper first on the
Symposium symposium. active inference do
Institute you can head over this will be
the fourth applied active inference
Symposium you can check out the
recordings and transcripts of the first
three register here will take you to a
form where you can add some information
and get registered here's the program
page first we have the interactive form
of the Symposium here you can click
right into the live streams November
13th and 14th there will be long live
streams on November 15th our partners at
fp1 will be hosting a Biore Regional
convening Newman games also has created
a metaverse space if anybody wants to
jump in explore there there are going to
be a lot of awesome presenters at the
Symposium if you want to check out more
you can look at the program
table you could read the abstracts and
also with the help of Maria we also
published the abstract book updating the
page now and
here are the abstracts for each of the
presenters so if you want a downloadable
form for the abstract book like it's a
conference
take a look at this
document if you want an interactive form
that's available
here when you
register you'll see at the top can we
share your registration information if
you leave it unchecked then we'll keep
it private if you check it we'll do a
few things first We'll add you to public
participants here's the list of
participants who opted into publicly
sharing information and then this was a
collaboration with Vladimir bin in the
GitHub repo active inference Institute /
Symposium over in
perplexity there are the scripts that
are used to do perplexity AI API calls
and two kinds of outputs on the
presenters and on the participants first
on the presenters for each of the
presenters there's a background research
profile so if you want to learn more
about a given researcher you can find
out more and then what was a lot of fun
and I hope people give some feedback on
this
and explore how we could continue to
version
this is in the participants again for
the participants who said yes opt me
in each of them who should I pick on
have three documents a profile a
learning plan and a project proposal set
of project
proposals so here we go here's a profile
a learning plan and a project
proposal for
Frasier this is using the information
that the person put into the form plus
using the perplexity API so if you want
to read more about the different
participants you could look at their
profiles like this and this is such
early early early days we have so many
interesting things coming like
this there's a learning plan for each
person so immediate next steps what
resources to look at objectives concrete
actions to take short-term
goals medium-term
developments different specific
resources of course synthetically
generated as a first draft however for
people who are thinking well how can I
get started with learning or who else is
out there in the community these are
helpful documents and lastly is in each
of the participant folders is three
project proposals of small medium and
large scope and each of them are
structured according to the H Meer
catechism so a set of questions what are
you trying to do how is it done what is
new who cares what are the risks how
much will it cost how long will it take
what are the checkpoints so here
for Frasier we have small project active
inference in visual
foraging medium project scaling active
inference models with deep neural
networks and longer term project
hierarchical active inference for
compositional lat structure and when I
go over to my
own short-term project Pro active
inference and ant colony
Behavior medium-term enhancing
populationbased
search longer term project active
inference for cognitive Security in
organizational design so pretty fun
we're looking forward to also developing
these scripts doing different kinds of
team and project assembly so this just
gives a first pass first scratch towards
the questions that we all have all year
round what is active inference how can
we learn how can we contribute to the
bigger picture how is active inference
useful what are the imple
implementations like what are people
doing with it those are the questions
that we ask at the Symposium so I hope
everybody who's listening in a timely
fashion registers and joins and engages
and for next year we will come back with
the fifth applied active inference
Symposium more and different work
more and different co-organizers and
sponsors so that's the first part of
this announcement about the Symposium
tomorrow and some of the things we've
done for
it second part of the announcement today
we snapshotted
the
document active inference Institute and
active inference
ecosystem it's published on zenodo as a
concatenated
PDF thanks to all the authors who
contributed in many awesome ways to this
document in the link that I'll put into
the YouTube live chat right now you can
engage with the interactive form and
then it was concatenated and put onto
zenodo using Koda print and PDF export
to
PDF this page and subpages that's pretty
much how we got the linear format from
the living vers
version I'll spend a little bit to give
some context on the structure of this
since why not we're here anyway and this
may make it more useful for
some we published version one of this
paper last year we collaboratively wrote
it in Google Docs so that was more like
linear collaborative editing and that
was getting pretty long and unwieldy and
a little bit hard to get situational
Awareness on what we didn't didn't have
in the document so moved over toota for
this V2 and it was a ton of fun if you
want a special kind of output you can
always go to that perplexity link and
continue the
conversation summarize this for me as a
haiku active inference thrives bridging
minds and Nature's flow learning as we
grow
so if you want to interact that way okay
here's the structure of this document
there's three sections up top then two
major body sections and then a final
discussion section so up top we have an
abstract
this overviews the sampling and the
living versioning nature of the document
briefly introduces active inference as a
unit unifying framework across
disciplines and highlights what this is
about which is the Institute and you
it's about participation in these
projects these organizations these areas
of Interest authors table of
authors and an active inference landing
page one that received many fascinating
comments and discussions on from the
sidelines lot of different introduct
points of curated guides to active
inference and again many different ways
that we
can continue to keep versioning it as
would only be proper so those are the
top three sections the main two body
sections here's the section on The
Institute The Institute is a registered
nonprofit organization in Delaware USA
summarizes what we do here's a little
bit about our
history how we got going in
2020 officially started in
2021 brought in the scientific Advisory
Board in
2022 kept working and had two courses
the physics as information processing
with Chris fields and the social
sciences course and then this year
developments of
2024 Mission Vision Values and principle
our mission is to support the
accessibility rigor and applicability of
active inference to act in first
serve more on our values and principles
Focus areas for The Institute and how
they're addressed by our directions
ongoing
directions next section has to do with
Institute or
organization here's an image of our
organization our morphology we have the
scientific Advisory
Board the board of
directors
officers these will continue to be
versions as we improve ad links
members we have organizational units
these are the or
units it administrative
unit the edu active education unit
Reiner Research
Unit there are the Institute programs
programs are specific modes of active
participation and
engagement there is
volunteering The
Internship
mentorship the fellows currently the
research fellow
philanthropy for those who might like to
donate or
connect grants including where possible
are pending and submitted
grants which we publish also on
zenodo Partnerships
organizational Partnerships and how this
can be a synergistic relationship and
our current
Partners the default open-source license
for all of our products unless otherwise
specified and some links to open source
repositories little bit of a description
of the kinds of support that we provide
in the ecosystem for researchers and
Learners a bit about our Communications
how we communicate internally and
externally quality performance and
growth evaluation across the participant
Institute and ecosystem
scale little bit more information on
Information Management Discord for those
who
partake newsletter monthly newsletter
we've done it since the very beginning
of the Institute and
Koda next is the section with Institute
projects so these are are long-term
projects that are
officially
e e
okay thanks Andrew we're back I'll just
pick up with the Institute projects
Journal
publishing ontology speaking writing
analyzing
actm active entity
ontology agent based onology from 2022
that we've versioned and developed in a
few different settings since some osum
this was the first part of this
announcement cogar ecosystem John Boy
research fellows
project educational standards and
qualifications a long running project
that is going to be very interesting in
the coming
year
farmworks decentralized AI for
personalized
Solutions fundamentals of active inform
textbook in progress by sanj
namjoshi generalized notation notation
GNN including some recent developments
on GNN using it to make reproducible
generative models knowledge engineering
The Meta analysis of the literature we
did with blue and RJ in
2022 and
H good to get these bugs out I'll try to
fix them before tomorrow Physics course
physics is information processing by
Chris
Fields RX andf fur. JL learning
group work we've been
that should work
now RX and fur .jl learning group social
science course and links to the front
end in that
curriculum software we're developing
active block fronts as well as active
infer
ANS systems approach how we learn and
apply systems engineering at The
Institute textbook group 6 and a half
cohorts and links to learn more about
working through the 2022 textbook
Tech Tree and links to where we're
working on that and videos and podcasts
not unlike the halting one listening to
now 500 plus live streams that's the
section on The Institute itself so it's
about the structure our principles
projects directions all that all work in
progress I won't spend as long on the
ecosystem
this is all outside the Institute
different priorities that we've heard
from people from the
ecosystem the way we think about the
ecosystems development growth and
structure ecosystem projects that we
know about that people have proposed and
are engaged in and then the beginning of
a sort of synoptic review living review
meta post meta analysis on active
inference and domains so each of these
and this is widely open for people who'd
like to Steward a given section like
economics someone could be a domain
curator or Steward help keep this
updated so that that link right there
could be sent to anyone like here's ACM
in economics this is the entry point so
anyone who wants to add more domains we
just added a few and there's also some
with a lot of discussion like
education lastly closing section of the
document is the discussion and future
directions so that constitutes the
documents which is downloaded as a 105
page PDF as
well closing out the announcement here
now thanks for listening hope to see you
at the Symposium hope that you enjoy the
document about us and the ecosystem and
see you around thank you bye